Vivek Kumar

Principal DevSecOps Engineer

SGPGI, Lucknow, 226014

Email - vivekyad4v@gmail.com

Linkedin - https://www.linkedin.com/in/vivekyad4v/ (most active)

Website - http://vivekyadav.me/

Github - https://github.com/vivekyad4v

StackOverflow - https://stackoverflow.com/users/3802507/vivekyad4v

Overview

- 10+ years of experience in DevOps / SRE / Cloud / Platform Engineering.
- Majorly working on cloud computing, cloud(available, scalable & secure) architecture, Infrastructure management, AWS cloud, container orchestration, Serverless frameworks, CICD, security, cost optimization, logging, monitoring, incident management.
- Objective of bringing Dev & Operations team together, put in a lot of automation, standards and best practices for continual business growth without much friction.

Skills

AWS Cloud - VPC, EC2, IAM, RDS, DMS, EC, ALB, ASG, ES, Cognito, SSO, S3, Cloudfront, EFS, ECS, ECR, Elasticbeanstalk, Route53, SES, SNS, SQS, Data pipeline, EKS, Lambda, Cloudwatch, WAF, Guarduty, Config, DynamoDB, Redshift, SFTP, API Gateway, SSM, Parameter store, Secrets manager, CodePipeline, Organizations, AWS MSK/Kafka, VPC Transit gateways, Security hub, Macie, Network firewall, Identity center, Client VPN, inspector, trusted advisor, config.

SCM - Bitbucket, Github

Languages - Bash, Golang, Python

<u>Infrastructure As Code</u> - Terraform, Cloudformation, Terraform Cloud <u>Containerization</u> - Docker Engine|Compose|Swarm.

<u>Orchestration</u> - AWS ECS, AWS EKS, Kubernetes, Docker Swarm. <u>CICD</u> - CodePipeline, Jenkins, TravisCI, Github actions, Bitbucket pipelines, ArgoCD, GitOps.

<u>Monitoring & Logging</u> - NewRelic, Logentries, ELK, Grafana, Prometheus, AWS Cloudwatch, SNS, PGanalyze, Slack, Squadcast/Pagerduty, Datadog, Coralogix.

<u>Serverless</u> - AWS Lambda, AWS API Gateway, AWS Cloudwatch, Golang, AWS SAM, SNS.

<u>Security</u> - SOC2, PCI, Pingsafe, Cloudflare Zero trust, 1password, AWS KMS, Vanta, Firewalls.

IDP - OKTA, AWS Identity center, OIDC.

Certifications



Experience

Kodo / Principal DevSecOps Engineer

September 2022 - Present, BANGALORE

- Managing & maintaining AWS cloud, highly available & scalable cloud architecture, Infrastructure automation & management, AWS cloud, container orchestration(ECS/EKS), Serverless frameworks, CICD, security, cost optimization, logging, monitoring & compliances.
- Managing application platform on EKS with API gateways, logging, monitoring, cloud controllers, custom controllers, CICD, authentication(IAM/IRSA) using Terraform, Helm & Kubectl.
- Following infra as code and GitOps principles.
- Focusing a lot more on security & compliances Cloudflare, Cloudflare Zero Trust, IDS/IPS, Firewalls, SOC2 compliance, PCI compliance, 1password, AWS KMS, Vanta.

BYJU's / DevOps Lead

October 2021 - Present, BANGALORE

 Managing a team focussed technically towards cloud computing, highly available & scalable cloud architecture, Infrastructure management, AWS cloud, container orchestration, Serverless frameworks, CICD, security, cost optimization, logging, monitoring.

Happay / DevSecOps Lead

October 2017 - October 2021, BANGALORE

- Managing applications hosted on AWS for Deployments, Analytics, Databases, Monitoring, Integrations etc.
- Worked on Data Migration & Analytical projects.
- Worked on security aspects for SOC2 & PCI compliances.
- Containerization and Microservices.

HashedIn Technologies / DevOps Engineer

June 2016 - October 2017, BANGALORE

- Managing applications hosted on AWS for Deployments, Analytics, Databases, Monitoring, Integrations etc.
- Worked on Containerizing most of the applications.
- Used Docker Swarm for Orchestration in a Data centre environment.
- Jenkins job as code (pipelines).

NTT Data / Senior System Administrator Associate

June 2015 - June 2016, BANGALORE

- Worked on HAProxy, F5 & A10(managed) load balancers.
- Worked on GlusterFS, AFS, NFA filesystems.
- Managed Kerberos and Bind DNS servers.
- Supported customer applications on Apache Tomcat.

RayMn & BR Technologies / Linux Administrator

July 2013 - May 2015, Lucknow

- Managed clients VPS in different hostings.
- Managed applications on LAMP, CPanel, WHM, Webmin, Virtualmin.
- Managed Squid proxy server.
- Configured OpenLDAP, NFS, PAM.
- Configured Nagios, Zabbix, NRPE, Monit, Observium for monitoring purposes.
- Configuring Kickstart, PXE/NetBoot, DHCP, NFS, TFTP, Samba & VNC servers.

Education

AKTU / B.Tech (Computer Science) / 70%

2009 - 2013, LUCKNOW

Kendriya Vidyalaya / Higher Secondary School / 79%

2009, PUNJAB

Kendriya Vidyalaya / Secondary School / 75%

2007, PUNJAB